<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Columbia Psychology Lab Preview</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Columbia Psychology Lab Preview</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Attention, Memory, and Perception Lab</title>
      <link>/aly/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/aly/</guid>
      <description>The Attention, Memory, and Perception Lab 
 In psychology, it is traditional to divide up cognition (and the brain) and study each component separately. For example, in your classes, you may read about attention, perception, and memory in different chapters of your textbook. In the Aly Lab, we explore how the brain’s “memory systems” contribute to attention and perception, and how attention in turn shapes what we perceive, remember, and predict.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Davachi Memory Lab</title>
      <link>/davachi/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/davachi/</guid>
      <description>   The Davachi Memory Lab 
 Hi we are the Davachi lab attention and memory a tension with memory for attention
  Contact  Role  Email      Nat  Lab Manager  zall@columbia.edu      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Authenticity, Choice, and Technology Lab</title>
      <link>/iyengar/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/iyengar/</guid>
      <description>The Authenticity, Choice, and Technology Lab The ACT Lab is actively seeking research assistants 

 The ACT (Authenticity, Choice, and Technology) Lab is looking for research assistants (for credit or unpaid) to work with Sheena Iyengar of the Columbia Business School over the semester and beyond. Sheena works in social psychology and specializes in subjects such as innovation, authenticity, and how choice influences decisions and perceptions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Couples Lab</title>
      <link>/couples/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/couples/</guid>
      <description>The Couples Lab The Couples Lab is not actively seeking research assistants 
In the Columbia Couples Lab we study dyadic processes (i.e. interactions between two individuals), particularly in health-relevant contexts. Our primary lines of research include how people co-experience stress, how people support each other through adversity, and how people cope with stress (e.g., do they co-ruminate?). We aim to understand how social relationships influence people’s functioning, especially during times of stress, as well as how the relationship itself functions during these adverse experiences.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Developmental Affective Neuroscience Lab</title>
      <link>/tottenham/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/tottenham/</guid>
      <description>The Developmental Affective Neuroscience Lab 
 Lab Description: We are scientists who conduct research on emotional development and associated neurobiology. Our research focuses on the process of development itself and how early experiences impact emotional behavior and brain development. Dr. Nim Tottenham is the Principal Investigator of the lab. Students in the laboratory work on projects covering a wide range of topics including neurobiological correlates of early adversity, emotion regulation, face processing, and temperament.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Higgins Lab</title>
      <link>/higgins/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/higgins/</guid>
      <description>The Higgins Lab The Higgins Lab is not actively seeking research assistants 
In the Higgins Lab, we study the motivational underpinnings of perceptions, judgments, decisions, and behaviors in a wide range of contexts. Ongoing projects in our lab explore how different fundamental motives influence how people relate to each other, navigate their social worlds, and pursue their goals. We embrace a motivated cognition framework in pursuing both basic and applied research questions</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
